<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Wenbin Mei</title>
    <link>https://wenbinmei.github.io/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Wenbin Mei</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Wenbin Mei</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/project/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Study Functional Constraint Regions for Crop Improvement</title>
      <link>https://wenbinmei.github.io/project/functional-constrain/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wenbinmei.github.io/project/functional-constrain/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Understanding the functional contribution of non-coding regions is a challenge for plant genomics. Many non-coding regions have regulatory function due to SV, promoter, enhancer, conserved non-coding sequence et al. Identify these functional constraint regions in the genome would help plant breeding to priority GWAS hits and improving the prediction accuracy of genomic selection model by exploiting biological prior. During my Ph.D., I identified conserved intron retention events across grass species, and subsets of these conserved intron retention events even have conservation across introns suggesting these introns are under functional constraint. In future, I am plan to focus on identifying the functional constraint regions in the genome and investigate their interaction between plant breeding, climate change, genome function, and natural selection.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crop Wild Relatives</title>
      <link>https://wenbinmei.github.io/project/crop-wild-relative/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wenbinmei.github.io/project/crop-wild-relative/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Crop wild relatives provide a tremendous amount of unexplored genetic variations for improving traits of human interest. Among these are many traits related to resistance against pests and diseases and tolerance of abiotic stresses relevant for climate change adaptation. Currently, I am working on structral variation in maize and maize wild relative teosinte. In future, I am planning to continue using crops and their wild relatives as my study system to understand the interface between plant breeding, climate change, genome function, natural selection, and long-term evolutionary dynamics.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Study Gene Regulation for Crop Improvement</title>
      <link>https://wenbinmei.github.io/project/gene-regulation-for-crop-improvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wenbinmei.github.io/project/gene-regulation-for-crop-improvement/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Gene regulation process can be viewed as molecular traits linking genotype to phenotype including chromatin structure, methylation, transcription, splicing, and translation. I am taking an integrative approaches including functional genomics, evolutionary genomics and statistical genomics to understanding the genetic basis of these molecular traits, regulation between these different molecular traits and their contribution to the phenotypes and the environmental adaptation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Study structural variation for crop improvement</title>
      <link>https://wenbinmei.github.io/project/structural-variation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wenbinmei.github.io/project/structural-variation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Structural variation (SV) is defined as rearrangements, gain or loss of genomic DNA sequences including deletion, insertion, inversion, and translocation. Copy number variant commonly refers to
deletions and insertions. SV has been shaping the genetic diversity and genome complexity and is essential for plant phenotypes such as copy number variation in GL7 contributing to grain size diversity in rice and retrotransposon insertion upstream an MYB transcription factor controlling the color of blood orange. Besides contributing to the phenotypes, SV plays an important role related to adaptation in the new environment, disease resistant and recently more evidence suggest structural variation is a primary driver of metabolite diversity. Currently I am using whole genome sequence from a single natural population of the maize wild relative teosinte to investigate evolutionary consequence and function of copy number variant.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
